(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 1,
"subtitles": 2
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
Twinkle Idol Christmas
さくらみこ200万人＆新衣装お披露目LIVE
Sakura Miko 2 Million Subscribers & New Outfit Reveal LIVE
重大告知あり！
Important Announcement Included!
すてきなホリデイ
Wonderful Holiday
作詞・作曲：竹内まりや　編曲：山下達郎
Lyrics/Composition: Mariya Takeuchi  Arrangement: Tatsuro Yamashita
近づいている冬の足音
The footsteps of winter are approaching.
耳を澄ませば聞こえる鈴の音
If you listen closely, you can hear the sound of bells.
寝ぼけた頭に響く目覚ましを
The alarm clock ringing in my sleepy head,
手さぐりで止めたあと雪の気配
After fumbling to stop it, I sense snow.
始まりを告げるすてきな季節が
The wonderful season that heralds the beginning...
Happy holidays, happy holidays What a glorious time of year!
すやすやと眠る子供たちの手に
In the hands of peacefully sleeping children,
抱かれたテディベアももう待ちきれない
The teddy bears they hold can't wait any longer.
クリスマスが今年もやって来る
Christmas is coming again this year,
悲しかった出来事を消し去るように
As if to wipe away the sad events.
さあ パジャマを脱いだら出かけよう
Now, let's take off our pajamas and head out.
少しずつ白くなる街路樹を駆け抜けて
Running through the street trees that are turning white.
華やぎ始めた 街は急ぎ足
The town, starting to brighten up, is moving at a quick pace
贈り物決まる頃 黄昏れてゆく
By the time gifts are decided, twilight is falling
かじかんだ指を ママが温めるね
Mama will warm your numbed fingers
Happy holidays, happy holidays. What a glorious time of year!
大切なものは みんなそばにある
Everything important is right by your side
穏やかな毎日が 続いてゆく
The peaceful days will continue
クリスマスがもう じきやって来る
Christmas is coming very soon
うれしさをかくせない 犬や猫まで
Even dogs and cats can't hide their joy
もみの木に灯る 明かりをうけて
Bathed in the lights of the fir tree
いつもよりやさしそうな パパの目が笑ってる
Papa's eyes, looking kinder than usual, are smiling
クリスマスは誰にでもやって来る
Christmas comes to everyone
もしひとりぼっちでも 寂しがらずに
Even if you're all alone, don't be lonely
心に住むソングに 呼びかけて
Call out to the song living in your heart
幼い頃の夢を 思い出してごらんよ
Try to remember your childhood dreams
クリスマスが 今年もやって来る
Christmas is coming again this year
悲しかった出来事を 消し去るように
As if to wipe away the sad events
さあ パジャマを脱いだら 出かけよう
Come on, let's change out of our pajamas and go out
少しずつ白くなる 街路樹を駆け抜けて
Run through the roadside trees that are gradually turning white
Happy happy holidays
Ah Whipしたケーキのような街は 好き！雪！本気マジック
Ah, the town is like a whipped cake. Love! Snow! Real Magic
空がくるコンフェッティは 冬のフェスタ祝う天使の羽よ Woo
The confetti coming from the sky are angels' wings celebrating the winter festa, Woo
白銀の国へ 出かけるの Go Go Go
Heading to the silver land, Go Go Go
雪の汽車が 街を駆け Choo Choo Choo
The snow train runs through the town, Choo Choo Choo
絵本みたいな景色を 君に見せてあげるから
I'll show you a scene like a picture book
願い込めて呪文さあ(さあ) 唱えて(さんはい)
Make a wish and chant the spell (come on), recite it (one-two)
ABCDドレミファソマジカルミラクルクル Pop!
ABCD Do-Re-Mi-Fa-So Magical Miracle Pop!
Ah Whipしたケーキのような街は 好き！雪！本気マジック
Ah, the town is like a whipped cake. Love! Snow! Real Magic
空がくるコンフェッティは 冬のフェスタ祝う天使の羽よ
The confetti coming from the sky are angels' wings celebrating the winter festa
Light Upしたオーロラ色の街は 好き！雪！本気マジック
The aurora-colored town lit up. Love! Snow! Real Magic
子供でいられたら Dream Land
If I could stay a child, Dream Land
Ladies and gentlemen, Welcome to Snow Miko!
ツンと冷たい季節が好き Love Love Love
I love the stinging cold season. Love Love Love
アイスも魔法もとけないように ヒューヒューヒュー
So that neither ice nor magic melts, Hugh Hugh Hugh
ずっとこのままじゃダメなの？
Is it no good to stay like this forever?
やっぱりドキドキしたいな
I really want to feel my heart thumping
未来求め呪文今(今) 唱えて(さんはい)
Seeking the future, chant the spell now (now), recite it (one-two)
1234金地火木土天海マジカルミラクルクル Pop!
1234 Mercury-Venus-Earth-Mars-Jupiter-Saturn-Uranus-Neptune Magical Miracle Pop!
Ah ホップしたウサギのような気分 好き！雪！本気Magic
Ah, feeling like a hopping rabbit. Love! Snow! Real Magic
大地がくれる元気 得たら 思い通り明日を生きていけるよ
If I get the energy the earth gives me, I can live tomorrow as I wish
まぶしい白に染まるハート君に 好き！雪！本気Magic
To your heart dyed in dazzling white. Love! Snow! Real Magic
大人のふりなんて いいじゃん
Pretending to be an adult is fine
I hear that beat from town... The cute angel will come down... This is my home I'll let you know NAMARA fantastic!
今日の寒さも 忘れるように（わすれちゃって）
So you can forget even today's cold (just forget it)
悩みだって悩みだって 凍らせて
Freeze all your worries, freeze them up
消せる魔法よ（もっかい！）
It's magic that can erase them (one more time!)
ABCDドシララシシュ マジカルミミクルクルクルPop!
ABCD Do-Si-La-La-Si-Shu Magical Mimikuru-kuru-kuru Pop!
Ah Whipしたケーキのような街は
Ah, the city that looks like a whipped cake
好き！雪！本気Magic
I love it! Snow! Serious Magic
空がくれるコンフェッティは
The confetti falling from the sky is
冬のフェスタ祝う 天使の羽よ
Angels' wings celebrating the winter festa
Light Upした オーロラ色の街は
The aurora-colored city lit up
好き！雪！本気Magic
I love it! Snow! Serious Magic
子供でいられたら Dream Land
If we could stay children, it's Dream Land
いいじゃん！
It's great!
君の前では私（もう一度）
In front of you, I'm... (once more)
らしくいて いいよね？
being myself, it's okay, right?
さくらんぼメッセージ
Sakuranbo Message
弱気で消した ジングル
A jingle erased by timidness
いつもドキドキだね 第一声
My first words are always heart-pounding
にゃっはろ〜！
Nyapparo~!
震えた声もノートの文字も
The trembling voice and the letters in the notebook
みんなみんな 手繋いで GO!
Everyone, everyone, hold hands and GO!
変わってるねって
You're strange, they say
そーなんだ
Is that so?
なんて言ったの？
What did you say?
まあいっか
Well, whatever
飲み込んじゃってきた言葉も
The words I've been swallowing down
君と笑った 声でほら咲いて
Look, they bloom with the voice that laughed with you
ばんざい！
Banzai!
こんな私でも
Even someone like me
モーマンタイ！
No problem!
好きだってねえほんと？
I love you, hey, really?
元気？わかりそう？
Are you well? Do you understand?
どっち？わかんない！
Which is it? I don't know!
さくらんぼメッセージ
Sakuranbo Message
受け取って いっせーのせで！
Receive it, on the count of three!
きっともっとキュンとしちゃうような
I'm sure it'll make your heart throb even more
さくらんぼメッセージ
Sakuranbo Message
つぼみにぎゅっと詰め込んで！
Pack it tightly into the bud!
君の前では私（もう一度）
In front of you, I'm... (once more)
らしくいて いいよね？
being myself, it's okay, right?
なんて返そっか
How should I reply?
没頭！
Absorbed!
顔がフットー！
My face is boiling over!
頭が！
My head!
素直がモットー！
Honesty is my motto!
ゲームの中なら get you!
If it's inside a game, get you!
攻略しちゃう？
Shall I win you over?
百発百中なのになぁ
Even though I never miss
どったんばったん踊ったなら
If I dance around all noisily
悩んじゃったって大騒ぎ
I make a big fuss even if I'm just worried
ずっキュンばっキュン スタートボタン 押せるかな？
Zu-kyun Ba-kyun, can I press the start button?
ちゃんと言ったっけ？
Did I say it properly?
どーだっけ？
How was it?
言わなきゃよかった？
Should I not have said it?
そーだっけ
Was that so?
抑え込んじゃって また焼きもち
Holding it back and getting jealous again
あー私なんて しゃがみそうになって
Ah, even I feel like crouching down
これが私だもん
But this is who I am
大賛成！
Huge approval!
行くよって ほらこっち
I'm going, look this way
右送っちゃう？
Send it right?
左送っちゃう？
Send it left?
まっすぐ！
Straight ahead!
さくらんぼメッセージ
Sakuranbo Message
春めいて待って 飛び立って！
Waiting for spring to bloom, then fly away!
そっとじっと キュンとしちゃう日も
Even on days when I quietly throb with emotion
さくらんぼメッセージ
Sakuranbo Message
瞳にぱっと 映るよ
It'll suddenly be reflected in your eyes
背中を押して メロディー
The melody pushes me forward
好きでいて いいよね？
It's okay to keep loving you, right?
誰かじゃなくて
Not someone else
君がいいって
I want it to be you
絶対！
Absolutely!
何度でも言うよ
I'll say it as many times as it takes
もう一同！
All together once more!
好きだってねえほんと！
I love you, hey, really!
元気？わかりそう？
Are you well? Do you understand?
どっち？わかんない！
Which is it? I don't know!
ほんとだー！
It's true!
さくらんぼメッセージ
Sakuranbo Message
受け取って いっせーのせで！
Receive it, on the count of three!
きっともっとキュンとしちゃうような
I'm sure it'll make your heart throb even more
さくらんぼメッセージ
Sakuranbo Message
つぼみにぎゅっと詰め込んで！
Pack it tightly into the bud!
君の前では私（もう一度）
In front of you, I'm... (once more)
らしくいて いいよね？
being myself, it's okay, right?
好きでいて いいよね？
It's okay to keep loving you, right?
はーい！にゃっはろ〜！ Twinkle Idol Christmas さくらみこ新衣装お披露目LIVEに来てくれてどうもありがとうございます！
Hi! Nyapparo~! Thank you all for coming to Twinkle Idol Christmas, Sakura Miko's new outfit reveal LIVE!
そしてみんな、メリークリスマース！イェ〜イ！
And everyone, Merry Christmas! Yay!
えー本日、クリスマスはなんと みこちゃんのホロライブ加入記念日でもあります！
Um, today, Christmas, is also Miko-chan's Hololive debut anniversary!
おめでとー！ありがとー、ありがとー！
Congratulations! Thank you, thank you!
えーそして、お披露目したこちらの衣装は200万人記念で作らせていただいた新衣装のルームウェア... ルームウェア衣装となっております！
And this outfit that I've revealed is the new room-wear... room-wear outfit that was made to commemorate reaching 2 million subscribers!
かわいいでしょ〜。
Cute, right?
あのね、いつも新衣装で悩んでるんですけど、
You know, I'm always worried about my new outfits,
作りたいなってずっと持ってったんだけどなかなかね、
but I've always wanted to make this one.
踏み切れなかったこのルームウェアをね 200万人記念で作らせてもらいました。
I finally got to make this room-wear for my 2 million sub milestone!
いいあいでじゃ、これね。
It was a good idea, right?
そして、ちょ見ていただくんですけど、
And, please take a look at this,
こちら！じゃじゃーん！
This one! Ta-da!
ヘアバンド！これみこぴのヘアバンドになってます。
A hairband! It's a Mikopi-themed hairband.
ちょっとふわふわしてるかわいいし。
It's a bit fluffy and cute.
ま、このピンもいっぱいついててイヤリングもかわいくて。
It has lots of pins, and the earrings are cute too.
あとこのさくらんぼになってるんでしょめっちゃネックレスかわいい。
And look at this cherry necklace, it's so cute.
んで、このね、だぼっとしたニットに、
Then, with this loose-fitting knit sweater,
ま、ちょっとセクシーなね、ルームウェアとなってますこれね。
it's a bit of a sexy room-wear outfit.
あのちょっと中々なね みこちゃんおへそを見せないんですけど、
Miko doesn't usually show her belly button, but...
おへそが見えます！
You can see my belly button!
ちょとあの若干、まあね、寒くなるとね食べたくなって若干ぷにってる気もしなくもないけど、
It's a bit... well, when it gets cold I want to eat, so it might be a bit pudgy, but...
まあまあまあ気にしたら負けですからね。
Well, you lose if you worry about it too much.
大丈夫、健康的な範囲だからね。大丈夫大丈夫。
It's fine, it's within a healthy range. It's fine.
ということで、あのね、隅々までちょっと見ていただきたいんですけど、
So, I want you to take a good look at every detail, but...
もっとね見ていただきたいところがあります。
There's something else I want you to see.
見て！このお部屋かわいい！
Look! This room is so cute!
本日のライブ、なんとトリバルゴンさんにね製作を、あの、お願いさせていただきまして作ってます。
For today's live, we actually asked Tribaragon to design this room.
本当にどうもありがとうございます。めっちゃかわいいの。
Thank you so much. It's really cute.
もう本当にねみこぴとかね、このソファーとかね、
Everything from the Mikopis to this sofa,
めちゃくちゃ細かく作っていただいております。
they've put so much detail into it.
このあともね、ちょっとね、びっくりするギミックとかもありますのでお楽しみに。
There are some surprising gimmicks later on, so look forward to those.
じゃあね、あ、そうだハッシュタグだハッシュタグ。
Now then... Oh, right, the hashtag.
ハッシュタグはこちら！さくらみこ新衣装クリスマスライブでね、応援してください。
Here's the hashtag! Please use it to support me.
スクショもたくさん撮ってね。ちょっとスクショタイム！
Take lots of screenshots too. Time for some screenshots!
はい！きらーん！
Okay! Sparkle!
あ、かわいい！
Ah, cute!
かわいい！
Cute!
あ、かわいい！はいかわいい！
Ah, cute! Yes, cute!
はいかわいい！
Yes, cute!
はいかわいい！ということでね、みんなたくさん撮ったよね。
Yes, cute! So, everyone took lots of photos, right?
はい！お願いしまーす！
Yes! Please do!
そして、なんと最後に重大告知も、ありますので、
And, there's actually a major announcement at the end,
最後までぜひお見逃しなく！ありがと。よろしくね。
so please don't miss it! Thanks. I'm counting on you.
それじゃあ、次の曲いきますか！
Well then, shall we move on to the next song?
こちらにね、移動させていただきまして。
I'll just move over here.
はい！それじゃあ、次の曲、いくぞ！
Yes! Well then, here we go with the next song!
半端ないわ ぱっぱら ぱっぱら ぱっぱらっ (ヘイ！)
It's incredible! Pappara pappara pappara (Hey!)
限界突破 ぱっぱら ぱっぱら ぱっぱらっ (ヘイ！)
Breaking through the limits! Pappara pappara pappara (Hey!)
毎日半端ないわ ぱっぱら ぱっぱら ぱっぱらっ (ヘイ！)
Every day is incredible! Pappara pappara pappara (Hey!)
限界突破 ぱっぱら ぱっぱら ぱっぱらっ (ヘイ！)
Breaking through the limits! Pappara pappara pappara (Hey!)
明日の私に幸あれ
May I be happy tomorrow
最適温度 uh 遮るゴースト
Optimal temperature, uh, a ghost blocking it
八百万の 嫌な外的要素
Myriad unpleasant external factors
「何の気ない」と 超あっけらかんと
"It's nothing," being totally nonchalant
悪気もなく邪魔するどっかの誰かさんにバイバイ
Bye-bye to someone who interferes without malice
自分時間だらだらタイム確保 17時〜9時は死守マス
Securing my lazy me-time, strictly defending 17:00 to 9:00
さらに愛や恋やまいやも忘れずに
And don't forget about love, affection, and everyday life
とどのつまり オーバーワークは立ち入り禁止ですよって注意喚起もしてますよ
Basically, I'm even warning that overwork is strictly prohibited
ねえ楽しくて苦しくなくて生きてくって難しいな
Hey, it's hard to live while having fun and not suffering
だって安定 裏技 一夜だけ甘い蜜には罠がある
Because there are traps in stability, cheat codes, and sweet honey for just one night
やっ！
Yeah!
眠くなったら寝る
Sleeping when I'm tired
お昼過ぎに起きる
Waking up after noon
遊びたくて遊ぶ
Playing because I want to play
お腹減ったらご飯を食べる
Eating when I'm hungry
嬉しかったら笑う
Laughing when I'm happy
悲しかったら泣いてもいいんじゃない
It's okay to cry when I'm sad
明日の私のために今日もなんとか頑張るのさ
I'll do my best today for the sake of myself tomorrow
明日もう頑張らなくていいように頑張るのさ
I'll do my best so I don't have to work so hard tomorrow
怠惰じゃないや これ多分そうだ なんやでやることやっています！
It's not laziness, this is probably it, I'm doing what I have to do!
WHAT? & BUT 誰に知られなくたって別にいいから
WHAT? & BUT I don't care if no one knows
私には私のマイルール
I have my own rules
明日ラクするためにはハイチーズ
Say cheese so tomorrow can be easy
意外とこんな感じでラブアンドピースのある毎日を生きたいのです
Surprisingly, I want to live every day with love and peace like this
Don't be Don't be Don't be shy ドキドキしたいいたい
Don't be Don't be Don't be shy, I want to feel the excitement
Let Let Let me shine 明日天気になれ
Let Let Let me shine, let the weather be good tomorrow
To To To be excite 心もっと踊りたい
To To To be excited, I want my heart to dance more
Sunday Monday Tuesday Wednesday 木金土日月
Sunday Monday Tuesday Wednesday Thu Fri Sat Sun Mon
辛くなったら歌う
Singing when things get tough
ムカついたら愚痴る
Complaining when I'm frustrated
やりたいようにやる
Doing things my way
それができたら苦労しないわ
If it were that easy, I wouldn't be struggling
常に一喜一憂
Always going through ups and downs
適当にセーフリスクは回避しつつ
Appropriately avoiding safe risks
まぁまぁ頑張るのさ
I'll do my best in my own way
適当にまでは言うまいが
I won't go so far as to say "appropriately"
まぁ頑張るのさ
But I'll do my best
夢の中では…
In my dreams...
ずっとぐーたらしてやるんだ
I'm going to be lazy forever
誰かのためとかそんなんじゃなく明日の私のために (Fight!)
Not for someone else, but for the "me" of tomorrow (Fight!)
楽するために苦しいことも乗り越えちゃうんだからね (Fight!)
I'll even overcome painful things just to be at ease (Fight!)
やりたくないことやらないためにやりたくないことやれ (Fight!)
Do things you don't want to do so you don't have to later (Fight!)
あれこれって結果頑張れてる？
Wait, does this mean I'm actually doing my best?
私とってもえらいじゃないか！ (Fight!)
I'm actually doing great! (Fight!)
自分時間 堕落タイム確保 17時〜9時は死守マスト
Securing my time, my corruption time. Protecting 5pm to 9am is a must
さらに愛や恋や夢も忘れずに
And don't forget love, romance, and dreams
とどのつまり
In the end...
オーバーワークは立ち入り禁止ですよって注意喚起もしてますよ
I'm even giving a warning that overwork is forbidden
ねぇ楽しく苦なく生きてくって難しいな
Hey, living happily and without pain is hard
だって「安定」「裏技」「一夜漬け」甘い蜜には罠がある やっ！
Because "stability," "cheats," and "cramming," sweet nectar has traps. Yah!
眠くなったら寝る
When I'm sleepy, I sleep
お昼過ぎに起きる
I wake up after noon
遊びたくて遊ぶ
I play because I want to play
お腹減ったらご飯を食べる
When I'm hungry, I eat
嬉しかったら笑う
When I'm happy, I laugh
悲しかったら泣いてもいいんじゃない
When I'm sad, it's okay to cry
明日の私のために今日もなんとか頑張るのさ
For the "me" of tomorrow, I'll somehow do my best today
明日もう頑張らなくていいように頑張るのさ
I'll do my best so that I don't have to do my best tomorrow
半端ないぱっぱらっぱっぱらっぱっぱら (ヘイ！)
It's insane, pa-pa-ra-pa... (Hey!)
限界突破らっぱっぱらっぱっぱらっぱ (ヘイ！)
Breaking limits, pa-pa-ra-pa... (Hey!)
毎日半端ないぱっぱらっぱっぱらっぱっぱら (ヘイ！)
Every day is insane, pa-pa-ra-pa... (Hey!)
限界突破らっぱっぱらっぱっぱらっぱ
Breaking limits, pa-pa-ra-pa...
ねぇあたし知ってるよ きみがひとりモニタリングしてるの知ってるよ
Hey, I know. I know you're monitoring alone
ビクンビクン震えてさ 声もダダ漏れなんだわ
You're twitching and shaking, and your voice is leaking out
正直に言っちゃえよ バレてるんだし言っちゃえよ 効いてんの？
Just be honest and say it. I've already found out, so say it. Is it working?
普通普通 恥ずかしい？ みんな隠しているだけ もっほう
It's normal, normal. Are you embarrassed? Everyone is just hiding it. Mo-hou
モニタリング
作詞・作曲：DECO*27 編曲：DECO*27 & Rockwell & Hayato Yamamoto
Monitoring
Lyrics/Music: DECO*27 Arrangement: DECO*27 & Rockwell & Hayato Yamamoto
ねぇあたし知ってるよ きみがひとり涙してるの知ってるよ
Hey, I know. I know you're shedding tears alone
グスングスン凹んでさ 弱音ヒトカラ in the night
Sniffling and feeling down, singing complaints alone at karaoke in the night
朝が来るまで一勝コース もっと泣いたって 何度だって受け止めてあげる
A winning course until morning comes. Even if you cry more, I'll accept it over and over again
もう我慢しないで いっぱい出してね MWAH!
Don't hold back anymore, let it all out. MWAH!
お願いきみが欲しいの 慰めさせてシェイクシェイク 愛の才能で
Please, I want you. Let me comfort you, shake shake, with the talent of love
泣いてくれなきゃ 溢れてしまう 濡れていたい ねぇいいでしょう？
If you don't cry, it'll overflow. I want to be wet. Hey, it's okay, right?
舐め取って 飲み干したいんだってばってば MWAH!
I want to lick it up and drink it dry. I really do. MWAH!
お願いきみが欲しいの 頼り散らしてシックラブ なんて最路ね
Please, I want you. Relying on each other, sick love, what a path
分けてくれなきゃ きみの痛い 感じていたい ねぇいいでしょう？
If you don't share it, I want to feel your pain. Hey, it's okay, right?
吸い取って 救いたいんだってばってば
I want to suck it out and save you. I really do
見たい… 見たい… 見たい…
I want to see... I want to see... I want to see...
見たいのきみの中
I want to see inside you
見たい… 見たい… 見たい…
I want to see... I want to see... I want to see...
ねぇあたし知ってるよ きみがひとり悔しがってんの知ってるよ
Hey, I know. I know you're feeling frustrated alone
ズキュンズキュン高まるじゃん きみを推すことをやめない
My heart is thumping more and more. I won't stop supporting you
ねぇあたし知ってるよ きみはできる子知ってるよ
Hey, I know. I know you're a capable person
つらい時は弱い位で丁度いい あたしそれでも好きだよ MWAH!
When it's tough, being weak is just right. I still love you. MWAH!
お願いきみが欲しいの 名前を呼んでいつだって 会いに参上
Please, I want you. Call my name, anytime, I'll come to see you
きみはひとりだ だから歌う ひとりじゃない もういいでしょう？
You are alone, that's why I sing. You're not alone. It's enough, isn't it?
ソロプレイはお仕舞いなんだってばってば
Solo play is over. I really mean it
きみが病めるときも あたしそばにいるわ
Even when you're sick, I'll be by your side
いつも見守っているわ そうよ怖くないのよ
I'm always watching over you. Yes, it's not scary
MWAH!
お願いきみが欲しいの 慰めさせてシェイクシェイク 愛の才能で
Please, I want you. Let me comfort you, shake shake, with the talent of love
泣いてくれなきゃ 溢れてしまう 濡れていたい ねぇいいでしょう？
If you don't cry, it'll overflow. I want to be wet. Hey, it's okay, right?
舐め取って 飲み干したいんだってばってば MWAH!
I want to lick it up and drink it dry. I really do. MWAH!
お願いきみが欲しいの 頼り散らしてシックラブ なんて最路ね
Please, I want you. Relying on each other, sick love, what a path
分けてくれなきゃ きみの痛い 感じていたい 抱いていたい
If you don't share it, I want to feel your pain. I want to hold you
吸い取って 救いたいんだってば
I want to suck it out and save you
ねぇあたし知ってるよ きみがひとり涙してるの知ってるよ
Hey, I know. I know you're shedding tears alone
グスングスン凹んでさ 弱音ヒトカラ in the night
Sniffling and feeling down, singing complaints alone at karaoke in the night
朝が来るまで一勝コース もっと泣いたって 何度だって受け止めてあげる
A winning course until morning comes. Even if you cry more, I'll accept it over and over again
もう我慢しないで 出してってば さあ
Don't hold back anymore, let it out. Come on
ずっとといっしょ！
作詞・作曲・編曲：タカニシクタ
Always Together!
Lyrics/Music/Arrangement: Takanishikuta
ずうっといっしょ！
Zutto Issho!
充電器を貸して！
Give me the charger!
またあなたのせいで あたし減った
It decreased again because of you
充電見逃して
Missed the charge
またあたしのせいで 帰れなくなった
Couldn't go home again because of me
繋がっていようね 消耗戦に持ち込んで
Let's stay connected, dragging into a war of attrition
お互いに足を引っ張ったアオハル
Aoharu where we pulled each other's legs
沈殿した思い出で ずっといっしょ！
Forever together with precipitated memories!
参観日にだって 誰からも見られていない気がしたんだ
Even on visit days, I felt like no one was watching me
散々しに勝って 昼の街に期待しないようにしたんだ
Winning over the scatter, I tried not to expect anything from the midday town
そうやって守った 孤独さえめちゃくちゃになった
The loneliness I protected that way was also messed up
あたい いつだって死にたくて仕方ない
I always want to die so much
こんな顔 大事にしたいと思えないもん
I can't believe I want to treasure a face like this
共に過ごした日々が ささやかな幸せが
May the days we spent together, the modest happiness
かけがえのないトラウマになってたらいいな
Become an irreplaceable trauma
はなればなれなんて 誰かがつかせたバグだよね？
Being apart is just a bug someone planted, right?
あなたの一生の後悔として 添い遂げるよ
I'll stay with you as your lifelong regret
Q. 大切なものって、なあに？
Q. What is the most important thing?
A. 今失くしたそれ
A. That which you just lost
あたしと間違いを犯しちゃったんだ
You've made a mistake with me
取り返しがつかないね
There's no turning back
健やかになるときも病めるときも グロウ履歴の中で ずっといっしょ！
Through health and sickness, together forever in our growth history!
もうちょっとふつうに 悲しいこと悲しいと思いたかった
I wanted to think of sad things as sad, a bit more normally
長調のチューンに 感情移入して楽になりたかった
I wanted to feel at ease by empathizing with major chord tunes
「せいぜい一生懸命に生きてくださいね」
“Please live your life as hard as you can!”
あたい いつだって死にたくて仕方ない
I always want to die so much
あんな歌の言いなりになっていたくないの
I don't want to become at the mercy of a song like that
あなただけひとりで あたしの目を塞いで
All alone, by closing my eyes
幸せになろうなんて 思わないで
Don't you dare think about becoming happy
髪を乾かしてくれた夜から
Since the night you dried my hair
あたしは壊されたんだよ
I have been broken
あなたの一生の後悔として 添い遂げるよ
I'll stay with you as your lifelong regret
外れなくなってしまった 指輪みたいに
Like a ring that I can't take off anymore
何度もずっとフラッシュバックしている 最低だよ
It's flashing back again and again, it's the worst
一緒にいた時の方が あたし可愛かったなあ
I was cuter when we were together
あなたの一生の後悔として 添い遂げるよ
I'll stay with you as your lifelong regret
Q. 大切なものって、なあに？
Q. What is the most important thing?
A. 今失くしたそれ
A. That which you just lost
あたしと間違いを犯しちゃったんだ
You've made a mistake with me
取り返しがつかないね
There's no turning back
健やかになるときも 病めるときも
Through health and sickness
他の誰かと眠っていても
Even if you are sleeping with someone else
お揃いの悪夢で ずっといっしょ！
Together forever in a shared nightmare!
天天天国地獄国
作詞 yuzen(SUI) / 作曲 Alababa(SUI)
Ten Ten Tengoku Jigoku Goku
Lyrics: yuzen(SUI) / Music: Alababa(SUI)
天天天天天天天天
Ten ten ten ten ten ten ten ten
天天天国地獄国！
Heaven, Heaven, Heaven, Hell, State!
Open Sesame
闇と光の交わるfanatic
Fanatic where darkness and light cross
今宵味わうpsychedelic
Enjoying psychedelic tonight
踊り絡まりあうzodiac
Zodiac dancing and intertwining
恋の駆け引きのtie-break
Tie-break of love's tactics
飾らない存在 ただ気を惹きたい
Unadorned existence, just want to attract attention
夢見心地 触れ合い 惑わせたい
Dreamy feeling, touching, wanting to confuse
曖昧 溶けない cocktailは甘い
Ambiguous, undissolving cocktail is sweet
鮮やかな赤いeye 見つめて限界
Looking at vivid red eyes, reaching the limit
月夜に誘われ
Invited by the moonlit night
天使と悪魔と 天使と悪魔と 天使と悪魔が
Angels and demons, angels and demons, angels and demons
たまさか接した
Happened to touch
天国 地獄の 天国 地獄の 天国 地獄の
Heaven and Hell, Heaven and Hell, Heaven and Hell's
狭間で出会った
Met in the gap
天使と悪魔と 天使と悪魔と 天使と悪魔が
Angels and demons, angels and demons, angels and demons
集って踊れば
If they gather and dance
天国 地獄の 天国 地獄の 門が開く
The gates of Heaven and Hell, Heaven and Hell open
闇と光の交わるfanatic
Fanatic where darkness and light cross
今宵味わうpsychedelic
Enjoying psychedelic tonight
踊り絡まりあうzodiac
Zodiac dancing and intertwining
恋の駆け引きのtie-break
Tie-break of love's tactics
Dead Alive Dead Alive
Death Death Death
Birth Birth Birth
Dead Alive Dead Alive
Death Death
Birth Birth
Death! Birth! Yes! Let's Go!
生きた魂をtrayに置いて
Place the living soul on the tray
めくる5枚のcard 揺れる炎
Flip 5 cards, flickering flame
先にあなたがraiseしたなら
If you raise first
もう迷わない glass飲み干して
No more hesitation, drink up the glass
今夜all-in 譲れないこの勝負
All-in tonight, can't give up this match
いま、天国と地獄をつなぐ門が開いてゆく。
Now, the gate connecting heaven and hell is opening.
天使と悪魔、死者と生者が入り乱れ、踊り、笑い。
Angels and demons, the dead and the living mingle, dance, and laugh.
すべては混沌の中に飲み込まれてゆく。
Everything is being swallowed into chaos.
それは世界の終焉であり、
It is the end of the world,
新たなる始まりでもあるのだった。
and also a new beginning.
Dead Alive Dead Alive
Death Death Death
Birth Birth Birth
Dead Alive Dead Alive
Death Death
Birth Birth
Death Birth Death
天 天 天 天 天国 天
Heaven heaven heaven heaven heaven heaven heaven
天 天 天 天 天国 地獄
Heaven heaven heaven heaven heaven hell
天 天 天 天 天国 天
Heaven heaven heaven heaven heaven heaven heaven
天 天 天 天 天国 地獄
Heaven heaven heaven heaven heaven hell
月夜に誘われ 天使と悪魔が
Lured by the moonlit night, angels and demons
天使と悪魔が
Angels and demons
たまさか接した 天国 地獄の
Accidentally touched, the ecstasy of heaven and hell
恍惚消えない 果てない moon-night
Ecstasy won't fade, an endless moon-night
天国 地獄の
Heaven, hell's
狭間で出会った 天使と悪魔が
Met in the gap, angels and demons
天使と悪魔が
Angels and demons
天使と悪魔が 集って踊れば
Angels and demons, if they gather and dance
天国 地獄の
Heaven, hell's
狭間で出会った 天使と悪魔が
Met in the gap, angels and demons
天使と悪魔が
Angels and demons
天使と悪魔が 集って踊れば
Angels and demons, if they gather and dance
dance dance dance
天 天 天 天 天国 天
Heaven heaven heaven heaven heaven heaven heaven
天 天 天 天 天国 地獄
Heaven heaven heaven heaven heaven hell
天 天 天 天 天国 天
Heaven heaven heaven heaven heaven heaven heaven
天 天 天 天 天国 地獄
Heaven heaven heaven heaven heaven hell
clumsy trick
作詞・作曲・編曲：渡辺和紀
歌：さくらみこ
clumsy trick
Lyrics/Composition/Arrangement: Kazunori Watanabe
Vocals: Sakura Miko
回想中熱くなり お茶いかが？
Getting hot during reminiscence, how about some tea?
冷静に大人で
Calmly acting like an adult
ハートは君にまだ教えずに
Without telling you my heart yet,
ご相談チラチラと
glancing over for advice
余裕 身に着けて言う お相手はYou？
Wearing confidence, I ask, is it You?
ドラマのようなことしない女優
An actress who doesn't do things like in dramas
噛めば噛むほど美味しい Lady
The more you bite, the more delicious, Lady,
例に甘え方を見せてほしい
I want you to show me an example of how to be spoiled
はみ出したい ん～変われないの
I want to break out, mmm~ I can't change,
自由型のいい子は好き放題
a freestyle good girl does as she pleases
その塩梅 も～わからないの
That balance, I don't know anymore,
優しいふりしてただ煽ってる
pretending to be kind while just teasing
要求はさりげなく お茶濁し
Demands are casual, dodging the point,
嬉しさ誤魔化し
hiding my joy
反省会駆け引きを学びたい
A reflection meeting, I want to learn tactics,
裏技をつらつらと
listing secret tricks one after another
至急きっかけのキュー！
Urgent, the cue for the chance!
慌ててもCute そんな事なんて仕立てないIQ
Even if flustered, Cute, an IQ that wouldn't set up such a thing
あの手この手も出来ない Lady
Can't use this or that trick, Lady,
例におどし方まとめてほしい
I want you to summarize how to threaten me, as an example
遠慮して ん～はしけないの
Holding back, mmm~ I'm restless,
まるっと上手くリードしたいけど
I want to lead perfectly but...
そのボーダー も～超えられないの
That border, I can't cross it anymore,
そもそも話まだ隠してる
to begin with, I'm still hiding the story
(読めない 読めない) 恋は
(Can't read, can't read) Love is
(読めない 読めない)
(Can't read, can't read)
そっと口角上げ君を 魅せ君を…
Softly raising the corners of my mouth, to charm you, to you...
(包み包み)
(wrapping, wrapping)
そっと心タップ君を… あぁ君を
Softly tapping the heart, you... ah, you
(包み包み)
(wrapping, wrapping)
知りたい
I want to know
はみ出したい ん～変われないの
I want to break out, mmm~ I can't change,
自由型のいい子は好き放題
a freestyle good girl does as she pleases
その塩梅 も～わからないの
That balance, I don't know anymore,
優しいふりしてただ待ってもっと
pretending to be kind, just waiting for more
ん～はしけないの
mmm~ I'm restless
まるっと上手くリードしたいけど
I want to lead you perfectly, but...
そのボーダー もう超えらんないの
I can't cross that border anymore.
そもそもの話 まだ隠して
About the very beginning, still hiding it...
見つめてる
...and staring at you.
Snow halation
不思議だね いまの気持ち
It's strange, this feeling right now.
空から降ってきたみたい
It feels like it fell from the sky.
特別な季節の色が
The colors of this special season...
ときめきを見せるよ
...show me the excitement.
初めて出会った時から
From the moment we first met...
予感に騒ぐ心のMelody
...my heart's melody buzzes with anticipation.
とめられないとまらない なぜ
I can't stop it, it won't stop, why?
届けて 切なさには
Send it, for this sadness...
名前をつけようか “Snow halation”
...should we give it a name? "Snow halation"
想いが重なるまで 待てずに
Can't wait until our feelings overlap.
悔しいけど好きって純情
It's frustrating, but loving you is pure-hearted.
微熱の中 ためらってもダメだね
Even if I hesitate in this slight fever, it's no good.
飛び込む勇気に賛成 まもなくStart!!
I agree with the courage to dive in, it's about to start!!
音もなく気配もなく
Without a sound, without a sign...
静かに運命は変わる
...fate changes quietly.
これからの未来に胸の
In the future to come, my heart's...
鼓動が早くなる
...beating gets faster.
例えば困った時には
For example, when I'm in trouble...
すぐ駆けつけて 抱きしめたくて
...I want to run to you right away and hold you tight.
どこにいてもどこでも Fly high
No matter where you are, anywhere, fly high.
急いで いつの間にか
Hurry up, before I knew it...
大きくなりすぎた “True emotion”
...my "True emotion" grew too big.
夢だけみてる様じゃ つらいよ
It's painful just to be dreaming.
恋人は君って言いたい
I want to say that you're my lover.
優しい目が とまどってるイヤだよ
I don't like your kind eyes looking bewildered.
このまま一気に愛情 あずけて Please!!
Just like this, all at once, entrust your love to me, please!!
届けて 切なさには
Send it, for this sadness...
名前をつけようか “Snow halation”
...should we give it a name? "Snow halation"
想いが重なるまで 待てずに
Can't wait until our feelings overlap.
悔しいけど好きって純情
It's frustrating, but loving you is pure-hearted.
微熱の中 ためらってもダメだね
Even if I hesitate in this slight fever, it's no good.
飛び込む勇気に賛成 まもなくStart!!
I agree with the courage to dive in, it's about to start!!
Snow halation
はい！みんな楽しんでくれてますかー？
Hi! Is everyone having fun?
ゲストもね、たくさん来てくださいました。みんなありがとー。
Lots of guests came too. Thank you, everyone.
そして見てください！
And look!
ステージもちょっとね、ぐるっと回転して、外にやってきました。すごくないですか？
The stage rotated a bit, and we've come outside. Isn't it amazing?
ちょっとイルミネーションもね、綺麗でね。
The illuminations are also beautiful.
もうクリスマスって感じで。
It really feels like Christmas.
ちょっと若干肌寒いですが。ねー。
It's a little bit chilly, though. Right?
もうすごい綺麗だよね。
It's so beautiful.
見て、すごい、すごい。
Look, amazing, amazing.
わぁー。
Wow.
はい。どうもありがとうございました。
Okay. Thank you very much.
そして、なんと次で、最後の曲になるんですが...
And, well, the next one will be the last song...
なんと次の曲は、新曲です！
Believe it or not, the next song is a new song!
わぁー！
Yay!
みこちゃん、ファーストアルバム以来のね、ソロの新曲となります。
It's Miko-chan's first solo new song since her first album.
ソロライブを経て、みこがまた新たな一歩を踏み出す曲となっております。
Following the solo live, this is a song where Miko takes another new step forward.
それでは、聞いてください。
Now, please listen to it.
咲き誇れアイドル。
Sakiphokore Idol.
アイドルだから
Because I'm an idol
挑み続けるんだ
I'll keep challenging
君と夢見るんだ
Dreaming with you
不器用で悪いか
Is being clumsy bad?
咲き誇るよ
I'll bloom in full glory
咲き誇れアイドル
作曲 HoneyWorks, MARUMOCHI 作詞・編曲 HoneyWorks
Sakiphokore Idol
Composition: HoneyWorks, MARUMOCHI Lyrics/Arrangement: HoneyWorks
初のイベント 需要なしデフォ
First event, default with no demand
そんな私が夢を見ました
Such a person like me had a dream
アイドルという生き方
The way of life called being an idol
憧れて
Admiring it
「無敵エリート」
An "invincible elite"
笑顔はチート
With a cheat-like smile
こんな私を見てくれる君
You, who watches someone like me
好きなとこはどこですか？
Where is your favorite part?
わがままを許して
Please forgive my selfishness
ステージ経験値
Stage experience points
涙にじんで
Blurred by tears
それでも絶対負けたくない
Even so, I definitely don't want to lose
桜にメッセージ乗せて届け
Send the message on cherry blossoms
愛であふれますように
May it overflow with love
アイドルだから
Because I'm an idol
挑み続けるんだ
I'll keep challenging
君と夢見るんだ
Dreaming with you
不器用で悪いか
Is being clumsy bad?
咲き誇れ
Bloom in full glory
妄想だけじゃ終わらせない
I won't let it end just as a delusion
私らしく桜色
In my own cherry blossom color
ね？
Right?
磨いたスキル
Polished skills
実力発揮
Demonstrating ability
楽しめる日も増えてきたんだ
The days I can enjoy have also increased
アイドルとして生きてる
Living as an idol
君のおかげ
Thanks to you
アホ毛はキュート
The cowlick is cute
勝ち確ルート
A path to certain victory
そんな私についてきてよね！
Please keep following me!
ドジなとこも許されて
Forgiven even for being clumsy
最強じゃん！
Isn't that the strongest?
痛いの痛いの
Swallow the pain
グッと飲み込んで
Deep down
笑顔で笑顔増やしたいな
I want to increase smiles with a smile
桜前線が君の街に
As the cherry blossom front
春を届けるように
Brings spring to your town
アイドルだけは
Just being an idol
譲りたくないんだ
Is something I don't want to give up
君に魅せたいんだ
I want to charm you
理想へ挑むよ
I'll challenge my ideals
駆け抜ける
And run through
最高景色見せてあげる
I'll show you the best view
信じていて 桜を
Believe in me, in the cherry blossoms
さあ皆で咲かそう
Now, let's all bloom together
満開のピンクで世界染めて
Dyeing the world in full-bloom pink
あぁ
Ah
この涙はね
These tears
悲しい方じゃないから安心して
Aren't the sad kind, so don't worry
綺麗だね
It's beautiful, isn't it?
アイドルだから
Because I'm an idol
挑み続けるんだ
I'll keep challenging
君と夢見るんだ
Dreaming with you
不器用で悪いか
Is being clumsy bad?
咲き誇れ
Bloom in full glory
妄想だけじゃ終わらせない
I won't let it end just as a delusion
私らしく桜色
In my own cherry blossom color
ね？
Right?
みんなー！ Twinkle Idol Christmas
Everyone! Twinkle Idol Christmas
新衣装お披露目ライブを見てくれてどうもありがとう！
Thank you so much for watching the new outfit reveal live!
ここで告知が３つあります！
I have three announcements to make here!
まずは、こちら！
First, is this!
200万人記念ルームウェア衣装お披露目記念グッズが発売されます！
Commemorative goods for my 2 million subscribers roomwear outfit reveal will be on sale!
キービジュアルは、おるだん先生に描いてもらいました。
The key visual was drawn by Ordan-sensei.
いつもありがとうございます！
Thank you as always!
イラストのテーマは、お部屋でのんびりしているみこです。
The theme of the illustration is Miko relaxing in her room.
それでは、一つずつ見ていきましょう！
So, let's take a look at them one by one!
まずは、こちら！
First, is this!
リバーシブルブランケット！
Reversible Blanket!
表にはみこぴー、裏にはみこの大きなイラストが描いてあります。
There's Mikopi on the front, and a large illustration of Miko on the back.
丸めて包まれると、みんながみこぴーのぬいぐるみになっちゃうよ！
If you roll it up and wrap yourself in it, you'll become a Mikopi plushie!
続いて、みことおそろい 35Pヘアバンド！
Next, the matching Miko 35P Hairband!
みこの新衣装とおそろいのヘアバンドです！
It's a hairband that matches Miko's new outfit!
毎日使いができるアイテムでーす！ 使ってね！
It's an item you can use every day! Please use it!
次は、みこの愛用 35Pマグカップです！
Next is Miko's favorite 35P Mug!
お耳がついているマグカップなんだよ！
It's a mug with ears on it!
忠実に再現できました！
We were able to recreate it faithfully!
飲み物を入れてもよし、小物入れにするもよし、
You can put drinks in it, or use it as a small item holder.
素敵なおうち時間のお供に使ってね！
Please use it to accompany your wonderful time at home!
最後は、ルームウェアみこの35Pぎゅっ♡おねんねぬいぐるみです！
Lastly, the Roomwear Miko's 35P Gyu♡ Sleeping Plushie!
ルームウェア衣装のみこがぬいぐるみになりました！
Miko in her roomwear outfit has become a plushie!
みんなも一緒におやすみしようね！
Let's all sleep together!
フルセットはこんな感じです！
This is what the full set looks like!
そしてそして、フルセット特典はポストカードです！
And also, the full set bonus is a postcard!
今回は、箔押しの複製サインとメッセージ付きになっております！
This time, it comes with a foil-stamped duplicate signature and message!
みんな、ぜひぜひ購入してくださいね！
Everyone, please be sure to buy it!
告知２つ目はこちら！
The second announcement is this!
本日初披露した新曲「咲き誇れアイドル」が本日0時から配信開始！
The new song I performed for the first time today, 'Saki Hokore Idol', will be available from midnight today!
ファーストソロライブを終えて、次のステージに向かっていく気持ちをHoneyWorksさんに書き下ろしていただきました！
HoneyWorks wrote this song about my feelings of heading to the next stage after finishing my first solo live!
そしてそして、この後「咲き誇れアイドル」のMVがプレミア公開となります！
And also, the MV for 'Saki Hokore Idol' will have its premiere after this!
とっても可愛いので、みんなたくさん聴いて見てくださいね！
It's really cute, so please listen to it and watch it many times!
告知３つ目はこちら！
The third announcement is this!
なんと！ さくらみこ、鳴門鯛焼本舗のコラボが2026年も決定しました！
What! Sakura Miko and Naruto Taiyaki Honpo's collaboration is confirmed for 2026 too!
なんと、4回目ですよ！
This is the fourth time!
え、今回の開催期間は2026年2月20日から3月31日まででーす！
The event period this time is from February 20 to March 31, 2026!
やったー！
Yay!
本当にね、こんなに長く続いているのは、みんなのおかげでもありますし、
Really, the reason this has lasted so long is thanks to all of you,
鳴門鯛焼本舗さん、本当にありがとうございます！
and Naruto Taiyaki Honpo-san, thank you so much!
詳細情報は、後日またXなどで告知するので楽しみにしていてくださいね！
I'll announce detailed information on X and other platforms at a later date, so please look forward to it!
今日は本当にありがとう！
Thank you so much for today!
みんな、メリークリスマス！
Everyone, Merry Christmas!
おつみこでした！ バイバーイ！
Otsumiko! Bye bye!